<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Filtering on Shashank&#39;s Home</title>
    <link>https://mr-markovian.github.io/tags/filtering/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Filtering on Shashank&#39;s Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Shashank Roy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 11:15:58 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mr-markovian.github.io/tags/filtering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ensemble Kalman Filters</title>
      <link>https://mr-markovian.github.io/post/chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mr-markovian.github.io/post/chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>Kalman filter is a sequetial state estimation algorithms which performs the filtering-step recursively based on the assumption of linearity and gaussian density functions of the system which allows it to recursively implement the bayesian posterior calculation by simply updating mean and covariance whenever observations are available.
Proposed by G.Evensen, Ensemble Kalman filters are a Monte-Carlo approch of approximation of the original Kalman filter.The filter employs ensemble representation of probability distributions as a collection states drawn from the respective pdfs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metaheuristic Optimization and evolutionary algorithms: How nature solves it&#39;s problems</title>
      <link>https://mr-markovian.github.io/post/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mr-markovian.github.io/post/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A short introduction to Data Assimilation</title>
      <link>https://mr-markovian.github.io/post/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mr-markovian.github.io/post/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Data assimilation research addresses two problems of inverse modeling which are filtering and prediction. Filtering is defined as the sequential estimation of the posterior distribution in phase space of the state of a physical system based on a priori assumed model and available observations. Filtering is followed by prediction, where the goal is to quanitfy the the future of the system and it&amp;rsquo;s flow dependent uncertainty which accounts for possible source of error.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
